<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on mgb</title><link>https://mgb247.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on mgb</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 22:16:35 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mgb247.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Airlift Dream</title><link>https://mgb247.github.io/posts/the-airlift-dream/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 22:16:35 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://mgb247.github.io/posts/the-airlift-dream/</guid><description>On the 1st day of Eid, 10th of July, in the morning, I got a call from my manager.
He asked me to cancel all the orders except the Eid ones. I thought that maybe we got more orders than we were expecting. Right after that call, I got another call from our Platform Integrity Lead, he told me that the Eid orders were not landing on the warehouses and shared a video call link to join.</description></item><item><title>Tapping into Request Context, from anywhere, in NodeJS</title><link>https://mgb247.github.io/posts/request-context/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 19:03:44 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://mgb247.github.io/posts/request-context/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s world of microservices, NodeJS has become the go to runtime platform to build and deploy server applications on. It&amp;rsquo;s easier to implement, faster to integrate and to some extent manageable to scale. This specially catches the eyes of new startups who plan to deploy multitudes of microservices in a span of a few months.
While NodeJS is one of the top choices to build these servers, it definitely has its problems.</description></item><item><title>The Single Thread King that is Event Loop</title><link>https://mgb247.github.io/posts/event-loop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 19:22:15 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://mgb247.github.io/posts/event-loop/</guid><description>Whenever a new software project is born, on top of the priority list is the environment or framework in which it will be developed. In the software engineering world, there are multitudes of frameworks in which an idea can be engineered. For example, to create a webapp, we have a never ending list of options which may include a few well known frameworks like ASP .NET Framework on the C# side, Laravel on the PHP side and NestJS, ExpressJS, KoaJS, AdonisJS, MeteorJS and WhatnotJS on the NodeJS side.</description></item></channel></rss>